window.__examLoadCallback({
  "title": "General_Aptitude-_CSE - General_Aptitude-_CSE — Slot 17 (12 Questions)",
  "duration": 33,
  "sections": [
    {
      "name": "General_Aptitude-_CSE — Slot 17",
      "questions": [
        {
          "id": 1,
          "question": "<p>Given digits 2, 2, 3, 3, 3, 4, 4, 4, 4 how many distinct 4 digit numbers greater than 3000 can be formed? <br><br><strong>(GATE CSE 2010)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>50</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>51</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>52</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>54</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>B.</b> <p>51</p>",
          "marks": 2,
          "negative_marks": 0.67,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/2373/gate-cse-2010-question-65#a_list\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 2,
          "question": "<p>5  skilled workers can build a wall in 20 days; 8 semi-skilled workers can build a wall in 25 days; 10 unskilled workers can build a wall in 30 days. If a team has 2 skilled, 6 semi-skilled and 5 unskilled workers, how long it will take to build the wall? <br><br><strong>(GATE CSE 2010)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>20 days</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>18 days</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>16 days</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>15 days</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>D.</b> <p>15 days</p>",
          "marks": 2,
          "negative_marks": 0.67,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/2372/gate-cse-2010-question-64#a_list\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 3,
          "question": "<p>Modern warfare has changed from large scale clashes of armies to suppression of civilian populations. Chemical agents that do their work silently appear to be suited to such warfare; and regretfully, there exist people in military establishments who think that chemical agents are useful tools for their cause.\n<br><br>\nWhich of the following statements best sums up the meaning of the above passage: <br><br><strong>(GATE CSE 2010)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>Modern warfare has resulted in civil strife.</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>Chemical agents are useful in modern warfare.</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>Use of chemical agents in warfare would be undesirable.</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>People in military establishments like to use chemical agents in war.</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>D.</b> <p>People in military establishments like to use chemical agents in war.</p>",
          "marks": 2,
          "negative_marks": 0.67,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/2371/gate-cse-2010-question-63#a_list\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 4,
          "question": "<p>Hari(H), Gita(G), Irfan(I) and Saira(S) are siblings (i.e., brothers and sisters). All were born on 1st January. The age difference between any two successive siblings (that is born one after another) is less than three years. Given the following facts:\n<br><br>\ni.   Hari's age + Gita's age &gt; Irfan's age + Saira's age<br>\nii.  The age difference between Gita and Saira is one year. However Gita is not the oldest and Saira is not the youngest.<br>\niii. There are no twins.<br><br>\nIn what order they were born (oldest first)? <br><br><strong>(GATE CSE 2010)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>HSIG</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>SGHI</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>IGSH</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>IHSG</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>B.</b> <p>SGHI</p>",
          "marks": 2,
          "negative_marks": 0.67,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/2370/gate-cse-2010-question-62#a_list\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 5,
          "question": "<p>If 137+276=435 how much is 731+672? <br><br><strong>(GATE CSE 2010)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>534</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>1403</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>1623</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>1513</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>C.</b> <p>1623</p>",
          "marks": 2,
          "negative_marks": 0.67,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/2369/gate-cse-2010-question-61#a_list\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 6,
          "question": "<p>The question below consists of a pair of related words followed by four pairs of words. Select the pair that best expresses the relation in the original pair.\n<br>\nUnemployed : Worker <br><br><strong>(GATE CSE 2010)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>fallow : land</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>unaware : sleeper</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>wit : jester</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>renovated : house</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>A.</b> <p>fallow : land</p>",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0.33,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/2368/gate-cse-2010-question-60#a_list\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 7,
          "question": "<p>25  persons are in a room. 15 of them play hockey, 17 of them play football and 10 of them play both hockey and football. Then the number of persons playing neither hockey nor football is: <br><br><strong>(GATE CSE 2010)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>2</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>17</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>13</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>3</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>D.</b> <p>3</p>",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0.33,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/2367/gate-cse-2010-question-59#a_list\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 8,
          "question": "<p>Choose the most appropriate word from the options given below to complete the following sentence:\n<br>\nIf we manage to __________ our natural resources, we would leave a better planet for our children. <br><br><strong>(GATE CSE 2010)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>uphold</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>restrain</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>cherish</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>conserve</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>D.</b> <p>conserve</p>",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0.33,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/2366/gate-cse-2010-question-58#a_list\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 9,
          "question": "<p>Which of the following options is the closest in meaning to the word given below:\n<br>\nCircuitous <br><br><strong>(GATE CSE 2010)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>cyclic</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>indirect</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>confusing</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>crooked</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>B.</b> <p>indirect</p>",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0.33,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/2365/gate-cse-2010-question-57#a_list\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 10,
          "question": "<p>Choose the most appropriate word from the options given below to complete the following sentence:\n<br>\nHis rather casual remarks on politics ________ his lack of seriousness about the subject. <br><br><strong>(GATE CSE 2010)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>masked</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>belied</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>betrayed</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>suppressed</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>C.</b> <p>betrayed</p>",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0.33,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/2364/gate-cse-2010-question-56#a_list\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 11,
          "question": "<p>The exponent of 11 in the prime factorization of 300! is <br><br><strong>(GATE IT 2008)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>27</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>28</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>29</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>30</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>C.</b> <p>29</p>",
          "marks": 2,
          "negative_marks": 0.67,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/3285/gate2008-it-24\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 12,
          "question": "<p>The Fibonacci sequence is the sequence of integers <br><br><strong>(ISRO CSE 2007)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>1, 3, 5, 7, 9, 11, 13</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>0, 1, 1, 2, 3, 5, 8, 13, 21, 34</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>0, 1, 3, 4, 7, 11, 18, 29, 47</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>0, 1, 3, 7, 15</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>B.</b> <p>0, 1, 1, 2, 3, 5, 8, 13, 21, 34</p>",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0.33,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/49629/isro2007-61\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        }
      ]
    }
  ]
});
